Guide to the New Leader Collection of Letters from Cuba TAM.039
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New Leader Collection of Letters from Cuba
1961-1963
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New Leader (New York, N.Y.: 1924)
TAM.039
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Contains anti-Castro letters by Cuban residents, solicited for a never-published supplement to the New Leader.
5 linear inches (1 box)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the New Leader in 1963. The accession number 1963.023 is associated with this gift.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Norman Jacobs of the New Leader, a liberal anti-communist periodical, solicited letters from Cubans for a special supplement on Cuba under Castro, that was never published.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains approximately 100 letters by Cuban residents to United States relatives and friends describing conditions in Cuba. The letters, all anti-Castro, describe every-day life, the fates of acquaintances, objections to the regime and provide contemporary anti-Castro jokes and rumors. The collection includes the original letters as well as English translations.
Arrangement
Within each series the folders are arranged alphabetically and numerically.
the collection is organized into two series:
Missing Title
1.Originals
2. Translations.
Correspondence.; Cuba -- Social conditions.; Communism -- Cuba.; Castro, Fidel, 1926-2016; Jacobs, Norman.; New Leader (New York, N.Y.: 1924)
- Series 1: Originals
  - Letters from Cuba (Nos. 1-58) Original Copies, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Cuba (to J. Godoy), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Translations
  - Letters from Cuba Before the Blockade, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters from Cuba After the Blockade, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Cuba, typed translations, sent to USIA (Nos. 1-10), 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Cuba, typed translations, sent to USIA (Nos. 11-25), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Cuba, typed translations, sent to USIA (Nos. 26-58), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Cuba, translated by A.M. Nicholson, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Cuba, miscellaneous, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Cuba, translated by Fagan, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from Cuba, uncorrected copies of translations, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)